> Lucas Gustavo Santana Silva

Contact lucas2.4@live.com

Profile

Lucas Santana is a technology enthusiast, that did his first job with web development at twelve years and, nowadays, keep even more passionate in this area. Has a great knowledge in Node.JS building back and front-end applications, having more depth in creating or refactoring smart back-end solutions, faster and maintainable for your business. He knows how its important build applications using best practices, and stay tuned in the community to discover new modern ways to escalate applications. In this way, he will help you to make useful and cheaper applications using Container based applications, Hybrid Cloud solutions, and will guide you to the best way of delivering your solutions with modern technologies, used in huge companies like Google, Facebook, Amazon, and others.

Experience

06/2020 - Actual | Full Stack Developer at Qualicorp | Remote

Principal Technologies: Node.JS, Vue.JS, Nuxt.JS, Neo4j (Graph Database), ElasticSearch, MySQL, Azure, WebSocket.

Competences: Working mainly on 'QVenda' Project, that consists on creating a web application to manage the entire workflow of selling a health plan, by over 35k brokers of Qualicorp in the entire Brazil to the final client. Responsible for creating/maintaining core APIs, that take cares the 'proposals' and contracts handling.

In parallel, acted on standalone projects to enhance our internal development process:

- Applications Logging and easily control.
- '.ENV' dynamically manager with live reloading to the APIs.

10/2018 - 06/2020 | Full Stack Developer at NTT Ltd. | São Paulo - Remote

Principal Technologies: Node.js, Javascript, TypeScript, APIs, Integrations, Angular, Java, Oracle DB, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Linux based servers, AWS, Continuous Integration, BPM, Scrum.

Competences: At this job I was hired to implement solutions for a product to automate company business. I've been a time implementing for this product called 'Fluig', after some experiences, I realized that I was creating things that are no scalable and depending a lot from TOTVS to fix bugs and keep development. So, I started to develop using Node.JS, Container Based applications, SPAs and APIs, to an internal NTT product, gaining more scalability and significant performance improvement in relation to the product that I used to implement (Fluig – a Java Monolithic application). I achieved a great gain to the company developing internal systems integration using WebSocket's, mainly for communicate with Oracle, with the main goal to automate NTT business process in a digital transformation project.

10/2016 - 09/2018 | IT Intern at ACER | São Paulo

Principal Technologies: BPM, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript & jQuery

Competences: Hired to IT Infrastructure Support, but also, I developed internal systems. A managing system for internal Sales, IT Helpdesk System, and also a new intranet portal, having gains in managing internal sales to employees, also improve supporting users.

10/2015 - 10/2016 | IT Helpdesk at PROMESP | São Paulo

Principal Technologies: Windows Server

Competences: In this job I was hired to scan medical record, but proactively started to manage local servers from the company and also support IT and systems.

Education

• 01/2016 - 12/2019 | Science Computer bachelor's degree

References

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucasgustavosantana/
- https://github.com/lucaslk10